250 Ocean Parkway #6G • Brooklyn, NY 11218 +1 (917) 821-9783 • colin@colinabartlett.com

### **PROFILE**

I'm an Engineering/Product Director and Senior Ruby Developer with 15 years experience building web applications and managing software development projects and teams. I have full-stack experience and am a dedicated practitioner of TDD. I enjoy providing business value to stakeholders beyond just writing code.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Co-owner at Kinetic Web Solutions, Limerick, PA (Jan 2001 - Jun 2010)

In 2001, I founded a web development firm. I took on a partner and grew it to 10 full-time employees. In 2006, I converted our operations from Microsoft ASP to Ruby on Rails and transitioned us to a Rails consultancy. I was responsible for all day-to-day operations, sales, marketing, and project management. I was a developer and oversaw all development, engineering, and systems administration.

## Senior Consultant at Xforty Technologies, Limerick, PA (Jun 2010 - Sep 2011)

In 2010, I sold Kinetic and began consulting with friends at Xforty. I worked on several Rails applications and dabbled in some PHP and other projects. In January 2011, I obtained Loosecubes as a customer and moved to New York to contract with them full-time for 9 months.

## Lead Developer at Loosecubes, Brooklyn, NY (Jan 2011 - July 2012)

Loosecubes hired me in September 2011 to lead their development team. I was involved with nearly all aspects of their Rails application since the beginning. For a time, I was their sole developer and, for a time, I worked along side an outsourced team. I helped to train numerous newly-hired engineers and shape development strategy for this early-stage start-up.

# Director of Engineering at AppStack, Temecula, CA (October 2012 - Present)

I started at AppStack as a Senior Developer and eventually moved up to manage the engineering team. As Director of Engineering, I not only contribute daily to the codebase, but manage team direction and goals, mentor junior developers, interact with management and stakeholders, and generally keep the ship afloat.

## **SKILLS**

Expert level Ruby and Rails experience. Full stack developer proficient in JavaScript. Specializing in Test Driven Development, with significant experience introducing teams to TDD best-practices. Advanced Git, Rspec, and Cucumber experience and intermediary Linux systems administration abilities. Extremely picky about well-formed git commits.

## **COMMUNITY**

Organizer of the Philly on Rails Ruby user group 2008 to 2011 and frequent presenter. Contributor to Rails and other open source projects.

### **EDUCATION**

Business Major at Northeastern University, Boston, MA, (2001)

#### **INTERESTS**

Traveling, cooking, reading, Russia. Proficient in conversational Russian.